47. The World's Oldest Sports. Soccer, baseball, volleyball, and golf. Humans
love sports. We play old ones. We invent new ones. We cheer for our favorite players and
cry over our losses. But how long have humans been playing sports
for fun? Which sports are the oldest? Cricket, the English sport, is among the oldest.
There have been international cricket matches since 1844, but the game is much older than
that. There are references to a sport called cricket as far back as the late 1500s when
it was a children's game. It became popular among adults in the 1600s. The rules were
officially recorded in 1744. Tennis is also quite old. It began in Europe. Experts believe
it was played in monasteries for entertainment in the 1300s. It was first played with a wooden
ball and with hands instead of rackets, but it evolved over time. It became popular among
French kings between the 1500s and the 1800s. That was when it got the name tennis and when
official rules were established. But by far, the oldest sport comes from the
new world. It's called Yulama and it comes from what is now Mexico. Yulama was played
on a long narrow court with two teams of four or five people at each end. Teams serve the
balls to each other and then team members try to move the balls along the court until
they score by hitting a ball past the other team's line. They can only hit the balls
with their hips and thighs. Yulama is not common now, but it is still sometimes played
today in parts of Mexico. It began as far back as 1500 B.C., which means Yulama has
been played for 3,500 years.